=== PAGE 1 ===
Academic
Grade 9 Assessment
of Mathematics
2010
SAMPLE ASSESSMENT QUESTIONS
Record your answers to the multiple-choice questions
on the Student Answer Sheet (2010, Academic).
Please note: The format of
this booklet is different from
that used for the assessment.
The items themselves remain
the same.

=== PAGE 2 ===
Multiple-Choice Grade 9 Assessment of Mathematics, 2010
1 What is the value of 6x2 when x 5 1 ? 4 Consider the expression below.
3
a 2 3x2(5x2 2 2x 1 1)
9
Which of the following is equivalent to
this expression?
b 2
3 a 8x2 2 2x 1 1
c 2 b 8x2 1 x 1 4
c 15x4 2 2x 1 1
d 4
d 15x4 2 6x3 1 3x2
2 Chris has a square garden with an area of 5 The cylinder below has a volume of
38.4 m2, as shown in the diagram.
150 cm3.
8 cm
He decreases the length of each side by
1.7 m to make a smaller garden.
Which is closest to the perimeter of the
smaller garden?
a 37 m
Which of the following is closest to the
b 32 m area of the lateral surface of the cylinder?
c 25 m
Hint:
d 18 m V 5 πr2h
cylinder
A 5 2πrh
lateralsurface
3 The sum of the perimeters of two shapes is a 38 cm2
represented by 13x 1 4y.
b 75 cm2
The perimeter of one shape is represented
c 150 cm2
by 4x 2 2y.
d 300 cm2
Which expression represents the perimeter
of the other shape?
a 9x 1 2y
b 9x 1 6y
c 17x 1 2y
d 17x 1 6y
2

=== PAGE 3 ===
Grade 9 Assessment of Mathematics, 2010 Open-Response
6 Part-Time Job
Ezre works part-time at a clothing store. He earns $80 per week plus 6% of the value of his weekly
sales.
This week Ezre earns $119.
What is the total value of his sales this week?
Show your work.
The total value of his sales is __________________.
3

=== PAGE 4 ===
Multiple-Choice Grade 9 Assessment of Mathematics, 2010
7 Consider the following chart and graph. 9 A sports company uses the equation
C 5 8t 1 5 to represent the relationship
Temperature Temperature
between the total amount charged to rent
in degrees in degrees
a canoe, C, in dollars and the rental time,
Celsius, C Fahrenheit, F
t, in hours.
5º 41º
15º 59º What is the initial charge to rent a canoe?
25º 77º
a $0
F
b $5
88008
c $8
66006
d $13
44004
22002
a0 Data on distance travelled and the number
C
–40 –30 –20 –10 00 10 20 30 40 of hours spent travelling are shown on the
––2200 graph below.
––4400 The line D 5 10n 1 30 is also shown on
the graph.
––6600
––8800
What temperature in degrees Celsius is
equivalent to ]20 8F?
a ]4 8C
b ]18 8C
c ]29 8C
d ]40 8C
8 A bus is rented for a class field trip. The
transportation cost for the trip is made up
Number of hours
of $225 to rent the bus, $50 for gas and
$2 for each bus seat. Which equation best represents the line
of best fit for the data shown?
Which relation below describes the total
transportation cost for the trip if C is the a D 5 5n 1 33
total cost in dollars and n is the number
b D 5 8n 1 23
of seats?
c D 5 10n 1 18
a C 5 ]2n 1 225
d D 5 12n 1 25
b C 5 ]2n 1 275
c C 5 2n 1 225
d C 5 2n 1 275
4
)mk(
dellevart
ecnatsiD
Distance Travelled vs. Time
D
D = 10n + 30
n
0

=== PAGE 5 ===
Grade 9 Assessment of Mathematics, 2010 Multiple-Choice
aa Tyler walks along a line leading from a b
motion sensor. The graph below shows
information about Tyler’s walk.
c
Which of the following is closest to Tyler’s
speed in metres per second as he walks
toward the motion sensor?
a 2.0
d
b 1.3
c 0.8
d 0.5
as Which graph represents the equation
1
P 5 ] n 1 5?
2
a
5
morf
ecnatsiD
)m(
rosnes
noitom
P
10
9
8
Distance from Motion Sensor vs. Time 7
D 6
5
4
3
4
2
1
3 n
0 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10
2
P
1 10
9
8
t
7
0 1 2 3 4 5
6
Time (s) 5
4
3
2
1
n
0 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10
P
10
9
8
7
6
5
4
3
2
1
n
P 0 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10
10
9
8
7
6
5
4
3
2
1
n
0 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10

=== PAGE 6 ===
Open-Response Grade 9 Assessment of Mathematics, 2010
ad What’s the Charge?
The table below represents the linear relationship between cost and repair time at an appliance store.
Repair time, t Cost, C
(h) ($)
3 205
6 385
8 505
Determine the initial value of this relationship. Show your work.
Initial value: _______________________
Is this relationship a direct or a partial variation?
Circle one: Direct variation Partial variation
Justify your answer.
6

=== PAGE 7 ===
Grade 9 Assessment of Mathematics, 2010 Open-Response
af Hot New Wheels
Cybelle and Peter each buy a car. The graph below represents the value of Cybelle’s car over time.
V
t
1 2 3 4 5
Peter’s car costs less than Cybelle’s. The value of both cars changes at the same rate.
Determine a possible equation to represent the relationship between the value of Peter’s car, V,
in dollars, and time, t, in years.
V 5 ___________________________
Justify your equation.
7
)$(
rac
fo
eulaV
Value of Car vs. Time
20 000
16 000
12 000
8 000
4 000
0
Time (years)

=== PAGE 8 ===
Multiple-Choice Grade 9 Assessment of Mathematics, 2010
ag Which of the following represents an aj The graph below represents the relationship
equation of a line? between distance and time on Javier’s walk.
a y 5 2x
D
b y 5 x2 2 5
20
c x2 1 y2 2 25 5 0
d 2x 1 3y 2 5 5 0 16
12
ah What are the slope, m, and y-intercept, b,
of the line represented by
8
3x 2 2y + 16 = 0?
a m = 3 , b = 8 4
2
b m = 2 , b = ]16 t
3 0 2 4 6 8 10
2 Time (s)
c m = ] , b = ]8
3
3
d m = ] , b = 16 How much greater is Javier’s speed in
2
section p than in section q?
a 0.5 m/s
b 1.5 m/s
c 2.0 m/s
d 3.0 m/s
ak The total cost of hiring Beth’s Plumbing
Services is represented by the equation
C 5 50t 1 70, where C is the total cost
in dollars and t is the time in hours.
Next month, the rate will change to $60 per
hour, but the initial charge will stay the same.
Which of the following describes how the
graph of the relation will change?
a The steepness of the line will increase.
b The steepness of the line will decrease.
c The vertical intercept will increase by
10 units.
d The vertical intercept will decrease by
10 units.
8
)m(
ecnatsiD
Distance vs. Time
q
p

=== PAGE 9 ===
Grade 9 Assessment of Mathematics, 2010 Multiple-Choice
al Consider the following graph. sa Last weekend, Jeremy travelled from his
home to a friend’s house. The graph below
y
represents the relation between D, the
5 distance from Jeremy’s home, and t, the
A 4 time spent travelling to his friend’s house.
3
2
1
B D
x
–5–4–3–2–10 1 2 3 4 5
–1
–2 C
–3
–4
–5
Which statement is false?
a The slope of AB is ]2.
t
b The slope of CD is 1.
c The y-intercept of the line through CD
is ]4.
This weekend, Jeremy travels to his friend’s
d The y-intercept of the line through AB house but leaves from school. Jeremy’s
is ]1. school is between his house and his friend’s
house.
If he travels at a faster rate this weekend,
s0 Janelle draws a line that passes through
how will the line representing this trip
the points (]1, 6) and (0, 3). If Janelle
compare to the line representing the
writes the equation of the line in
previous trip?
y 5 mx 1 b form, what are the values
of m and b? This new line will
a m 5 ]9 a start at a higher point and be steeper.
b 5 3
b start at a higher point and be less
b m 5 ]3 steep.
b 5 6
c start at the current point and be
c m 5 ]9 steeper.
b 5 6
d start at the current point and be less
d m 5 ]3 steep.
b 5 3
9
emoh
s’ymereJ
morf
ecnatsiD
Distance from Jeremy’s
Home vs. Time Spent Travelling
D
0
Time spent travelling

=== PAGE 10 ===
Open-Response Grade 9 Assessment of Mathematics, 2010
ss The New Line
A line has
• the same slope as the line represented by 4x 2 3y 1 15 5 0 and
• the same y-intercept as the line represented by 2x 1 y 1 6 5 0.
Determine an equation of this line.
Show your work.
10

=== PAGE 11 ===
Grade 9 Assessment of Mathematics, 2010 Open-Response
sd Event-full
At Lowell High School, the cost to attend special events depends on whether or not a student has
purchased a $10 discount card.
Option A: The student buys a discount card. The cost is $5 per event.
Option B: The student does not buy a discount card. The cost is $7.50 per event.
Graph the relationship between total cost and number of events for each option on the grid.
70
60
50
40
30
20
10
0 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10
Determine the conditions under which a student at Lowell High School should choose each option.
Justify your answer.
11
)$(
tsoc
latoT
Total Cost vs. Number of Events
C
n
Number of events

=== PAGE 12 ===
Multiple-Choice Grade 9 Assessment of Mathematics, 2010
sf Ella wants a rectangle with sh A garden is in the shape of a rectangle and
a semicircle as shown below.
• a perimeter of 100 cm and
• the largest possible area.
What are the dimensions of the rectangle
10 m
that satisfies her conditions?
10 m
a 10 cm 3 10 cm
7 m 7 m
b 20 cm 3 30 cm
c 25 cm 3 25 cm
20 m
d 40 cm 3 60 cm
Which of the following is closest to the
amount of fencing needed to enclose the
sg Consider the parallelogram shown below. garden?
10 cm a 60 m
W X
b 70 m
c 75 m
4 cm
d 85 m
Z P Y
7 cm
What is the perimeter of WXYZ?
a 28 cm
b 30 cm
c 31 cm
d 34 cm
12

=== PAGE 13 ===
Grade 9 Assessment of Mathematics, 2010 Multiple-Choice
sj The playing chips of a board game are sk Consider the diagram below.
stored in cylindrical plastic cases. The
plastic cases have a volume of 25 120 mm3 y
and a diameter of 40 mm.
Playing Chip Plastic Case 125(cid:31)
40 mm 40 mm
105(cid:31)
130(cid:31)
Which of the following is the value of y
in the diagram?
a 558
b 708
c 1258
d 1308
sl What is the sum of the interior angles of
a 12-sided regular polygon?
a 10808
Which of the following is closest to the b 18008
height of one playing chip if 50 playing
chips can fit tightly into the plastic case
c 19808
as shown above? d 21608
a 0.1 mm
b 0.4 mm
c 1.3 mm
d 2.5 mm
13

=== PAGE 14 ===
Open-Response Grade 9 Assessment of Mathematics, 2010
d0 Toy Sailboats
Emelina makes toy sailboats as shown below.
11 cm
4 cm 4 cm
Determine the total area of the shaded sails.
Show your work.
14

=== PAGE 15 ===
Grade 9 Assessment of Mathematics, 2010 Open-Response
da What’s Missing?
Consider the diagram below.
65(cid:31)
85(cid:31)
y
x
108(cid:31)
Complete the table below.
Justify your answers using geometric properties.
Angle measure Justification
x (cid:31) _________
y (cid:31) _________
15

=== PAGE 16 ===
Grade 9 Assessment of Mathematics
2010
Sample Assessment Questions: Academic
Answer Key
1. a b c d 9. a b c d 17. a b c d 25. a b c d
2. a b c d 10. a b c d 18. b c d 26. b c d
3. a b c d 11. b c d 19. a b c d 27. a b c d
4. a b c d 12. b c d 20. a b c d 28. a b c d
5. a b c d 13. Respond in booklet. 21. b c d 29. a b c d
6. Respond in booklet. 14. Respond in booklet. 22. Respond in booklet. 30. Respond in booklet.
7. a b c d 15. a b c d 23. Respond in booklet. 31. Respond in booklet.
8. a b c d 16. b c d 24. a b c d
End of Assessment
Answer Key—Sample Assessment Questions

=== PAGE 17 ===
Applied
Grade 9 Assessment
of Mathematics
2010
SAMPLE ASSESSMENT QUESTIONS
Record your answers to the multiple-choice questions
on the Student Answer Sheet (2010, Applied).
Please note: The format of
this booklet is different from
that used for the assessment.
The items themselves remain
the same.

=== PAGE 18 ===
Multiple-Choice Grade 9 Assessment of Mathematics, 2010
1 Tommy uses the proportion below to 3 Tierney goes to the movie theatre
determine the amount of butter, x, to and has $20 to spend on treats.
use with 120 grams of sugar in his
Soft drink $2.29
cookie recipe.
Chocolate bars $1.69
2 x Popcorn $3.49
5
3 120
She buys two soft drinks, a chocolate
How many grams of butter does Tommy bar and popcorn. She also pays 13% tax.
need?
How much change should Tierney receive
a 40 from her $20?
b 80 a $8.97
c 180 b $9.76
d 240 c $11.03
d $11.55
2 The chart below shows the mass and the
cost for different brands of cookies.
4 There are 260 Grade 9 students at a high
school and 80% of these students attend a
Brand Mass (g) Cost ($)
dance. Half the Grade 9 students who
1 200 1.99
attend the dance buy their tickets at
2 250 2.29 the door.
3 300 2.89
How many Grade 9 students who attend
4 450 4.29 the dance buy their tickets at the door?
a 40
Which brand costs the least per gram?
b 104
a Brand 1
c 130
b Brand 2
d 208
c Brand 3
d Brand 4
5 Which expression represents the volume
of a cube with a side length of x?
a x2
b x3
c 3x
d 6x
2

=== PAGE 19 ===
Grade 9 Assessment of Mathematics, 2010 Multiple-Choice
x 2
6 What is the value of the expression 1 2
3
when x = 18?
a 2
b 12
c 36
d 108
7 The cost of a phone call at a hotel is
determined by the formula C 5 0.35t 1 0.6
where C is the cost, in dollars, and t is the
length of the call, in minutes.
What is the length of a call that costs $5.85?
a 3 minutes
b 6 minutes
c 15 minutes
d 18 minutes
3

=== PAGE 20 ===
Open-Response Grade 9 Assessment of Mathematics, 2010
8 Fill ’Er Up
The table below shows the cost of water for three customers. They each pay the same cost per litre.
Amount Cost
(L) ($)
10 000 08.60
20 000 17.20
30 000 25.80
Frank pays $36.12 for water at the same rate.
Determine the number of litres of water that he purchases.
Show your work.
4

=== PAGE 21 ===
Grade 9 Assessment of Mathematics, 2010 Open-Response
9 Sail Away
Alain designs a sail in the shape of a triangle for a boat.
height
base
The base and height are equal. The area of the sail is 18 m2.
Determine the height of the sail.
Hint:
bh
A 5
2
Show your work.
The height of the sail is ___________.
5

=== PAGE 22 ===
Multiple-Choice Grade 9 Assessment of Mathematics, 2010
a0 Malia records the number of ice cream Which line of best fit is most appropriate
cones she sells each day and the maximum for the data?
daily temperature, as shown on the graph
a
below.
140
130
120
110
100
90
b
80
0 20 22 24 26 28 30 32 34
According to this graph, approximately
how many ice cream cones will Malia sell
on a day when the maximum temperature
is 36°?
a 80
c
b 110
c 115
d 135
aa This graph shows the relationship between
students’ marks and the number of classes
that they have missed.
d
6
dlos
senoc
fo
rebmuN
Number of Cones Sold vs. Temperature
N
t
Temperature (°C)
Number of classes missed
)%(
kraM
Number of classes missed
Mark vs. Number of
Classes Missed
M
n
)%(
kraM
M
n
Number of classes missed
)%(
kraM
M
n
Number of classes missed
)%(
kraM
M
n
Number of classes missed
)%(
kraM
M
n

=== PAGE 23 ===
Grade 9 Assessment of Mathematics, 2010 Multiple-Choice
as A student creates a table to show the
relationship between the side length of
a square and its area.
Side length Area
1 1
2 4
3 9
4 16
5 25
Which of the graphs below best represents
this relationship?
a
Side length
7
aerA
ad The square-based prism below has a
height of 3 cm.
Which table represents the relationship
A between the side length and the volume
of this prism?
a
l
0
b
b
Side length
c
c
d
d
aerA
A
l
0
Side length
aerA
A
l
0
0 Side length
aerA
3 cm
Side
Side
Hint:
V 5(area of base)(height)
Side length Volume
(cm) (cm3)
1 3
2 12
3 27
4 48
5 75
Side length Volume
(cm) (cm3)
1 3
2 6
3 9
4 12
5 15
Side length Volume
(cm) (cm3)
1 1
2 4
3 9
A
4 16
5 25
Side length Volume
(cm) (cm3)
l 1 1
2 8
3 27
4 64
5 125

=== PAGE 24 ===
Multiple-Choice Grade 9 Assessment of Mathematics, 2010
af The following graphs represent a linear c
relationship between temperature and time.
Which graph has a rate of change of ]4 °C
per hour?
a Temperature vs. Time
T
t
d
Time (h)
b
8
)C°(
erutarepmeT
10
8
6
4
2
0
1 2 3 4 5
–2
–4
–6
–8
–10
Temperature vs. Time
T
t
)C°(
erutarepmeT
Temperature vs. Time
T
t
10
8
6
4
2
0
1 2 3 4 5
–2
–4
–6
–8
–10
Time (h)
)C°(
erutarepmeT
10
8
6
4
2
0
1 2 3 4 5
–2
–4
–6
–8
–10
Time (h)
Temperature vs. Time
T
t
)C°(
erutarepmeT
10
8
6
4
2
0
1 2 3 4 5
–2
–4
–6
–8
–10
Time (h)

=== PAGE 25 ===
Grade 9 Assessment of Mathematics, 2010 Multiple-Choice
ag Sarah is running a 40 km race at a steady c
pace of 10 km/h.
Which equation represents the distance
Sarah has left to run after she starts if D
is the distance in kilometres and t is the
time in hours since she started the race?
a D 5 40 2 10t
b D 5 40 1 10t
c D 5 10 2 40t
d D 5 10 1 40t d
ah The equations for the cost of a pizza at
two restaurants are shown below, where C
represents the cost in dollars and t
represents the number of toppings.
Peppi’s Pizzeria C 5 9 1 3t
Tony’s Pizza C 5 12 1 2t
Which graph best represents the cost of a
pizza at each restaurant?
a C Tony’s
Peppi’s
t
Number of toppings
b
9
)$(
tsoC
20
15
10
5
0 1 2 3 4
C
Tony’s
Peppi’s
t
Number of toppings
)$(
tsoC
C Tony’s
Peppi’s
t
Number of toppings
20
15
10
5
0 1 2 3 4
)$(
tsoC
20
15
10
5
0 1 2 3 4
C
Peppi’s
Tony’s
t
Number of toppings
)$(
tsoC
20
15
10
5
0 1 2 3 4

=== PAGE 26 ===
Multiple-Choice Grade 9 Assessment of Mathematics, 2010
aj The graph below illustrates the relationship al The total cost of renting a car on weekdays
between the distance driven and the amount is represented by the graph below.
of gasoline in the tank of a car.
Amount of Gasoline vs.
Distance Driven
Distance driven (km)
How many litres of gasoline are in the
car’s tank when the distance driven is
300 km?
a 10
b 20
On weekends, the flat fee remains the same
c 40
but the cost per kilometre is less.
d 50
Which of the following statements is true
about the graph for weekends?
ak One day, the temperature at 5 p.m. is 4 8C. a The weekend graph goes through the
For the next 6 hours, the temperature drops point (0, 0).
2 8C every hour. What is the temperature
b The weekend graph stays the same as
at 11 p.m.?
the weekday graph.
a 2 8C
c The initial cost is the same but the
b ]2 8C weekend graph is steeper than the
weekday graph.
C ]6 8C
d The initial cost is the same but the
d ]8 8C
weekend graph is less steep than the
weekday graph.
10
)L(
enilosag
fo
tnuomA
Total Cost vs. Number of
Kilometres Driven
G
90
50
80
40
70
30
60
20
50
10
40
d
0 100 200 300 400 500 30
20
10
50 100 150 200 250
Number of kilometres driven
)$(
tsoc
latoT
C
Weekdays
n
0

=== PAGE 27 ===
Grade 9 Assessment of Mathematics, 2010 Multiple-Choice
s0 Parallel Pines Bowling Alley offers two
options.
A graph representing the cost of Option A
is shown below.
Cost vs. Number of Games
Option B charges $30 for unlimited bowling.
Which of the following is true?
a Option A is always cheaper.
b Option B is always cheaper.
c Option A is cheaper for fewer than
15 games.
d Option B is cheaper for fewer than
15 games.
11
)$(
tsoC
C
45
40
35
30
A
25 o n
pti
20 O
15
10
5
n
0 5 10 15 20
Number of games

=== PAGE 28 ===
Open-Response Grade 9 Assessment of Mathematics, 2010
sa Marathon Man
Manny is running a race at a constant rate. He records his distance from the starting line at particular
times as shown below.
Complete the table for this linear relationship.
Time, t Distance, D
(h) (km)
0.5 3.5
1.0
Distance vs. Time
1.5 10.5
D
2.0 14.0
3.0
5.0
Graph this relationship on the grid.
t
1.0 2.0 3.0 4.0 5.0
Time (h)
12
)mk(
ecnatsiD
36
34
32
30
28
26
24
22
20
18
16
14
12
10
8
6
4
2
0

=== PAGE 29 ===
Grade 9 Assessment of Mathematics, 2010 Open-Response
ss Gym Time
The graph below shows the relationship between the cost of renting a gym and the amount of time
the gym is used.
Cost vs. Amount of Time
C
200
180
160
140
120
100
80
60
40
20
t
0 1 2 3 4 5 6
Determine the hourly rental rate.
The hourly rental rate is ________________.
Show your work.
13
)$(
tsoC
Amount of time (h)

=== PAGE 30 ===
Open-Response Grade 9 Assessment of Mathematics, 2010
sd Bowling Variations
There are two bowling alleys in town.
The total cost of bowling at Ten Stripes Bowling is represented by the graph below. Ten Stripes
offers free shoe rental.
Total Cost vs. Number of Games
Ten Stripes
The total cost of bowling at Supreme Bowling is $4 for shoe rental plus $3 per game.
Complete the chart.
14
)$(
tsoc
latoT
C
18
16
14
12
10
8
6
4
2
n
0 1 2 3 4 5
Number of games
Ten Stripes Bowling Supreme Bowling
The initial value is . The initial value is .
Circle one: Circle one:
Direct variation Partial variation Direct variation Partial variation
Justification of choice of type of variation: Justification of choice of type of variation:

=== PAGE 31 ===
Grade 9 Assessment of Mathematics, 2010 Multiple-Choice
sf A rectangle is to have a perimeter of sg Gordon has a circular pool in his backyard,
120 m. The graph below shows the as shown below.
relationship between the area of the
rectangle and its width.
Area vs. Width
Width (m)
What is the width of the rectangle with
the largest area? Which of the following is closest to the area
of the lawn surrounding the pool?
a 30 m
a 33.5 m2
b 60 m
b 34.2 m2
c 120 m
c 201.5 m2
d 900 m
d 248.6 m2
15
)2m(
aerA
Pool
A
10 m
1000
800
20 m
600
400
200 Lawn
w
0 10 20 30 40 50 60
14 m

=== PAGE 32 ===
Multiple-Choice Grade 9 Assessment of Mathematics, 2010
sh The water container below needs to be sj An ice cream shop sells ice cream cones
filled. that each contain an average of 525 cm3
of ice cream. The ice cream is served from
3 cm the following cylindrical tub.
30 cm
5 cm
Ice Cream Tub 45 cm
Which of the following represents the volume,
in cm3, of water that fills the container?
About how many cones can be made from
a V 5 p(32)(5)
a full tub of ice cream with the dimensions
b V 5 p(1.5)(5) shown?
c V 5 p(2 3 3)(5) a 8
d V 5 p(1.5)2(5) b 16
c 60
d 242
sk A carpenter is building a rectangular gate
for a fence, as shown below.
x
35(cid:31)
y
110(cid:31)
What are the values of x and y?
a x 5 358, y 5 1108
b x 5 358, y 5 1458
c x 5 558, y 5 1108
d x 5 558, y 5 1458
16

=== PAGE 33 ===
Grade 9 Assessment of Mathematics, 2010 Multiple-Choice
sl Consider the diagram below.
104(cid:31)
y
What is the value of y?
a 288
b 768
c 1048
d 1528
17

=== PAGE 34 ===
Open-Response Grade 9 Assessment of Mathematics, 2010
d0 Get Trackin’
Ashley runs around the following track.
100 m
60 m
How many times must she run around the track in order to run a total distance of 4 km?
Show your work.
Hint:
1 km 5 1000 m
18

=== PAGE 35 ===
Grade 9 Assessment of Mathematics, 2010 Open-Response
da Digging Around
A hydraulic arm swings from Point B to Point A, as shown in the diagram below.
40º y
105º
x
A B
Determine the values of x and y.
Justify your answers using geometric properties.
Value Justification
x (cid:31)
y (cid:31)
19

=== PAGE 36 ===
Grade 9 Assessment of Mathematics
2010
Sample Assessment Questions: Applied
Answer Key
1. a b c d 9. Respond in booklet. 17. a b c d 25. a b c d
2. a b c d 10. a b c d 18. a b c d 26. a b c d
3. b c d 11. a b c d 19. a b c d 27. a b c d
4. a b c d 12. a b c d 20. a b c d 28. b c d
5. a b c d 13. b c d 21. Respond in booklet. 29. b c d
6. a b c d 14. a b c d 22. Respond in booklet. 30. Respond in booklet.
7. a b c d 15. b c d 23. Respond in booklet. 31. Respond in booklet.
8. Respond in booklet. 16. a b c d 24. b c d
End of Assessment
Answer Key—Sample Assessment Questions

